The King lives on!
Elvis is a drama, music, tv movie film directed by John Carpenter.
This biopic traces Elvis Presley’s life from his impoverished childhood to his
meteoric rise to stardom to his triumphant conquering of Las Vegas.
Elvis Presley, played by Kurt Russell.
Gladys Presley, played by Shelley Winters.
Vernon Presley, played by Bing Russell.
Red West, played by Robert Gray.
Colonel Tom Parker, played by Pat Hingle.
Priscilla Presley, played by Season Hubley.
Elvis is a 1979 American made-for-television biographical film aired on ABC.
It is directed by John Carpenter and stars Kurt Russell as Elvis Presley, and
marked the first collaboration between Carpenter and Russell.
After its success on television in the United States, a shorter re-edited version
of Elvis was released theatrically throughout Europe and Australia.
It was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture Made for Television, and for three Primetime
Emmy Awards (including Outstanding Lead Actor in a Limited Series or a Special for Russell).
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll, rock
star, biography, singing, superstar.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.